A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Pupil Placement Board, 1957-1966
Library of Virginia
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1957-1966., Extent: 20.75 cu. ft. (62 boxes) (Box 1-62)
  - Suberies IV. County Applications, 1961-1966., 12 boxes (4.2 cu. ft.) (Box 12-24)
    - Patrick, 1962-1965. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Pittsylvania, 1962-1966. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Powhatan, 1961-1966. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Prince Edward, 1964-1966. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Prince George, 1961-1962. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Prince George, 1963-1965. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Prince William, 1962-1965. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Princess Anne, 1961-1963. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Pulaski, 1959-1960. (Box 24 A, Folder 1)
    - Pulaski, 1962-1966. (Box 24 A, Folder 2)
    - Rappahannock, 1961-1966. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Richmond, 1962-1966. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Roanoke, 1960-1962. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Roanoke, 1963. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Roanoke, 1964. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Roanoke, 1965-1966. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Rockbridge, 1962-1966. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Rockingham, 1962-1965. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Russell, 1962-1966. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Scott, 1962-1966. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Shenandoah, 1962-1965. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Smyth, 1962-1965. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Southampton, 1962. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Spotsylvania, 1962-1966. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Stafford, 1961-1965. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Surry, 1964-1966. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Sussex, 1962-1964. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Tazewell, 1965. (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Warren, 1962-1966. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Washington, 1961-1966. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Westmoreland, 1962-1966. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Wise, 1962-1965. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Wythe, 1962-1966. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - York, 1961-1965. (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Subseries V. City Transfers, 1958-1966., 9.1 cu. ft. (26 boxes) (Box 27-53)
    This subseries contains forms sent by the Pupil Placement Board regarding student transfers, the majority of which are form memorandums stating either approved or denied. Denied files may contain a copy of the student's application, the originals of these applications can be found in the Application series, Special subseries (boxes 87-105), applications the board "did not consider" are interfiled with those denied. This subseries also contains, school board transfers, parent letters requesting transfer, and documents relating to lawsuits. Not all cities are represented and some requests have more documentation than others. Restricted envelopes contain student test scores and/or grades and are to remain sealed for 75 years from the date of creation in accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) and Codes of Virginia 2.2-3705.4 and 2.2-3705.1.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by location, forms within the folders are arranged alphabetically by students last name.
    - Alexandria, 1963-1964. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Alexandria - Approved, 1961. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Alexandria - Approved, 1962. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Alexandria - Aprroved, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Alexandria - Approved, 1964. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Alexandria - Denied, 1958. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Alexandria - Denied: Letters to Parents, 1958. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Blacksburg - Petition, 1963. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Bristol - Approved, 1964. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Charlottesville - Court Case, 1958. (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Charlottesville - Denied, 1958. (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Chesapeake - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Covington - Approved, 1964-1965. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Covington - Denied, 1964. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Danville - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Fredericksburg - Approved, 1961-1962. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Fredericksburg - Approved, 1963. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Fredericksburg - Approved, 1964. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Fredericksburg - Court Case, 1961. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Fredericksburg - Denied, 1961-1964. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Galax - Approved, 1961-1964. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Hampton - Administrative, 1962 Sept-Dec. (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Covington - Administrative, 1963 Jan-Mar. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Hampton - Administrative, 1963 Apr-June. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Hampton - Administrative, 1963 July-Sept. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Hampton - Administrative, 1963 Oct-Dec. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Hampton - Administrative, 1964 Jan-July. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Hampton - Administrative, 1964 Aug-Dec. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Hampton - Administrative, 1965. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Hampton - Approved, 1958. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Hampton - Approved, 1963. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Hampton - Approved, 1964. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Harrisonburg - Approved, 1964. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Hopewell - Appeals, 1962. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Hopewell - Appeals (Original denied letters), 1961. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Hopewell - Approved, 1963. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Hopewell - Court Case, 1963-1964. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Hopwell - Court Ordered, 1963. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Hopewell - Denied, 1963-1964. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Hopewell - Test Results, undated. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Lynchburg - Addresses and Distances, 1962-1963. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Lynchburg - Approved, 1962-1963. (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Lynchburg - Court Case, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Lynchburg - Court Case, 1962. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Lynchburg - Denied, 1961-1963. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Lynchburg - Test Scores, 1962. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Martinsville - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Norfolk - Administrative, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Norfolk - Administrative, 1962. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Norfolk - Administrative, 1963. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Norfolk - Administrative, 1964. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Norfolk - Approved, 1961. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Norfolk - Approved, 1962. (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Norfolk - Denied, 1958. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Norfolk - Denied, 1961. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk - Denied, 1962. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Norfolk - Test Scores, 1961. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Norton - Approved, 1963/1964. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Norton - Parent and Student Letters, 1963. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Norton - Test Scores, 1963-1964. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Petersburg - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Petersburg - Denied, 1962/1965. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Portsmouth - Approved, 1962/1964. (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Portsmouth - Denied, 1962. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Radford - Approved, 1961-1965. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Radford - Denied, 1963. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Richmond, 1962. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Richmond - Administrative, 1958. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Richmond - Appeals, 1962. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Richmond - Approved, 1961. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Richmond - Approved (A-K), 1962. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Richmond - Approved (L-R), 1962. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Richmond - Approved (S-W), 1962. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Richmond - Approved, 1963. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Richmond - Approved (A-Cl), 1963. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Richmond - Approved (Co-Je), 1963. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Richmond - Approved (Jo-P), 1963. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Richmond - Approved (R-Y), 1963. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Richmond - Approved, 1964. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Richmond - Approved (A-J), 1964. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Richmond - Approved (M-W), 1964. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Richmond - Approved, 1965. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Richmond - Approved - Richmond Public School, 1965. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Richmond - Case Histories, 1958. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Richmond - Court Case, 1957-1962. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Richmond - Denied, 1961. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Richmond - Denied (A-K), 1962. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Richmond - Denied (L-W), 1962. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Richmond - Denied, 1963. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Richmond - Denied, 1964. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Richmond - Denied, 1965. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Richmond - False Application, 1961. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Richmond - Harris, William Melvin, 1962-1963. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Richmond - Parent Letters, 1962. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Richmond - Parent Letters, 1963. (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Richmond - Parent Letters, 1964. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Richmond - Parent Letters, 1965. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Richmond - Procedure for African Americans to White Schools, 1964. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Richmond - Quarles, William Dunbar, Jr., 1962-1963. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Richmond - Special File, 1959. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Roanoke - Appeals, 1962. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Roanoke - Approved, 1961. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Roanoke - Approved, 1962. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Roanoke - Court Case, 1961-1962. (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Roanoke - Court Case (Exhibits), 1961-1962. (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Roanoke - Denied, 1961. (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Roanoke - Denied, 1962. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Roanoke - Hearing (1), 1961. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Roanoke - Hearing (2), 1961. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Staunton - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Staunton - Denied, 1963-1964. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Staunton - Parent Letters, 1965. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Staunton - Pending, 1959-1966. (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Suffolk - Approved, 1964. (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Beach - Approved, 1963. (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Beach - Approved (A-J), 1964. (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Beach - Approved (K-W), 1964. (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Williamsburg/James City - Approved, 1964. (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Winchester - Approved, 1962/1964. (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Winchester - Denied, 1961. (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Winchester - Hearing, 1962. (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Subseries VI. County Transfers, 1958-1966., 4.55 cu.ft. (13 boxes) (Box 40-53)
    This subseries contains forms sent by the Pupil Placement Board regarding student transfers, the majority of which are memorandums stating either approved or denied. Denied files may contain a copy of the student's application, the originals of these applications can be found in the Application series, Special subseries (boxes 87-105), applications the board "did not consider" are interfiled with those denied. This series also contains school board transfers, parent letters requesting transfer, and documents relating to lawsuits. Not all Counties are represented and some requests have more documentation than others. The County of King William along with King and Queen contain letters which directly reference "negro" and "indian" students. Restricted envelopes contain student test scores and/or grades and are to remain sealed for 75 years from the date of creation in accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) and Codes of Virginia 2.2-3705.4 and 2.2-3705.1.
    - Accomack - Approved, 1964-1965. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Accomack - Denied, 1965. (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Albemarle - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Amelia - Approved, 1964. (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Amherst - Approved, 1962. (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Amherst - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Amherst - Denied, 1961-1964. (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Arlington - Case Histories, 1958. (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Arlington - Court Case, 1958. (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Arlington - Materials, 1958. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Augusta - Approved, 1958. (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Augusta - Parent Letters, 1965. (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Bath - Approved, 1964. (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Brunswick - Approved, 1964. (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Campbell - Approved, 1964. (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Carroll - Approved, 1964. (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Charles City - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield - Administrative, 1962. (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Chesterfield - Administrative, 1964. (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Chesterfield - Approved (A-K), 1963. (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Chesterfield - Approved (L-W), 1963. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Chesterfield - Approved, 1964. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Chesterfield - Approved, 1966. (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Chesterfield - Court Case, 1962. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield - Denied, 1962. (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Chesterfield - Denied, 1963. (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Chesterfield - Denied, 1964. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Chesterfield - Denied, 1965. (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Chesterfield - Parent Letters, 1965. (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Chesterfield - Petition, 1964. (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Chesterfield - Protest, 1963. (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Chesterfield - School Lists, 1963. (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Chesterfield - School Lists, 1964. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Chesterfield - Test Scores, 1963. (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Clarke, 1964. (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Culpeper - Approved, 1963. (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Culpeper - Approved, 1964. (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Culpeper - Parent Letters, 1965. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Dickenson - Approved, 1962. (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Dinwiddie, 1963. (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Dinwiddie - Approved, 1964. (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Essex - Approved, 1963. (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Fauquier - Approved, 1963. (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Fauquier - Approved, 1964. (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Fauquier - Parent Letters, 1965. (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Floyd - Approved, 1961-1964. (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Franklin - Approved, 1965. (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Frederick - Approved, 1962-1964. (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Frederick - Denied, 1962-1964. (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Giles - Approved, 1964. (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Gloucester, 1962-1965. (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Goochlandn - Approved, 1965. (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Grayson, 1963-1964. (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Grayson and Pulaski - Appeals, 1960. (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Grayson - Approved, 1961-1964. (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Greene - Administrative, 1963. (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Greene - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Greene - Court Case, 1963-1964. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Greene - Denied, 1963-1964. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Halifax - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Hanover - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Henrico - Administrative, 1964. (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Henrico - Approved, 1962. (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Henrico - Approved, 1963. (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Henrico - Approved (A-J), 1964. (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Henrico - Approved (K-W), 1964. (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Henrico - Approved, 1965. (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Henrico - Denied, 1962-1964. (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Henrico - Parent Letters, 1962-1963. (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Henrico - Protests, 1965. (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - King and Queen - Approved, 1963. (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - King and Queen - Approved, 1964. (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - King and Queen - Approved (Pleasant Hill), 1964. (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - King George - Appeals, 1962. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - King George - Approved, 1962. (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - King George - Approved, 1963. (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - King George - Approved, 1964. (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - King George - Court Case (1 of 2), 1963. (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - King George - Court Case (2 of 2), 1963. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - King George - Denied, 1962. (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - King William, 1961. (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - King William - Approved, 1963. (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - King William - Court Case, 1961. (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - King William - Hearings, 1961. (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Lancaster - Denied, 1965. (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Lee - Administrative, 1964. (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Loudoun - Approved, 1962. (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Loudoun - Approved, 1963. (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Loudoun - Approved, 1964. (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Loudoun - Court Case, 1962-1963. (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Louisa - Approved, 1965. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Mecklenburg - Approved, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Mecklenburg - Resolution, 1965. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Middlesex, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Montgomery - Administrative, 1963. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Montgomery - Approved, 1961-1963. (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Montgomery - Approved, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Montgomery - Hearings, 1961. (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Montgomery - Parent Letters, 1963. (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Nansemond - Denied, 1965. (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - New Kent - Denied, 1965. (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - New Kent - Protest, 1965. (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Northampton - Approved, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Northampton - Denied, 1965. (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Page - Approved, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Patrick - Administrative, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Pittsylvania - Approved, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Powhatan, 1963. (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Powhatan - Approved, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Powhatan - Court Case, 1962-1963. (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Powhatan - Protest, 1965. (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Prince Edward - Court Case, 1959. (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Prince George, 1963-1964. (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Prince George - Administrative, 1963. (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Prince George - Administrative, 1964. (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - Prince George - Approved, 1963. (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Prince George - Approved (A-H), 1964. (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Prince George - Approved (I-Y), 1964. (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Prince George - Court Case, 1962-1963. (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Prince George - Court Case, 1962-1964. (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Prince George - Denied, 1961. (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Prince George - Denied, 1962. (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Prince George - Denied, 1963. (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Prince George - Denied, 1964. (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Prince George - Fort Lee, 1962-1963. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Prince George - Parent Letters, 1963. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Prince George - Petersburg Residents, 1962. (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Prince George - Student Lists, 1963-1964. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Prince William, 1961. (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Prince William - Approved, 1962. (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Prince William - Approved, 1963. (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Prince Wiiliam - Approved, 1964. (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Prince William - Hearings, 1961. (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Prince William - Test Scores, 1958. (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Princess Anne - Approved, 1962. (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Princess Anne - Denied, 1962. (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Pulaki - Approved, 1963. (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Pulaski - Approved, 1963. (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Pulaski - Court Case, 1962. (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Pulaski - Parent Letters, 1965. (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Roanoke, 1962. (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Roanoke, 1963. (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Roanoke - Administrative, 1962. (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Roanoke - Administrative, 1963. (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Roanoke - Administrative, 1964 Aug-Jan. (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Roanoke - Administrative, 1964 Dec-Sept. (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Roanoke - Administrative, 1965. (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Roanoke - Approved, 1964. (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Roanoke - Court Case, 1961. (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Roanoke - Denied, 1960. (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Roanoke - Denied, 1961. (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Roanoke - Denied, 1964. (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Roanoke - Denied, 1965. (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Rockbridge - Approved, 1964. (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Rockingham - Approved, 1964. (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Rockingham - Denied, 1963. (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Shenandoah, 1962. (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Shenandoah - Approved, 1963. (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Shenandoah - Approved, 1964. (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Spotsylvania - Approved, 1963-1964. (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Stafford - Approved, 1961-1964. (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Stafford - Denied, 1961-1962. (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Stafford - Court Case, 1961-1962. (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Stafford - Hearings, 1961. (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Stafford - School Board Plan, 1962. (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Warren - Approved, 1963. (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Warren/Rappahannock - Approved, 1964. (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Warren - Court Case, 1968-1960. (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Warren - Student and School Information, 1957-1958. (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Warren - Withdrawn, 1958. (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Wythe - Aproved, 1964. (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - York - Approved, 1963. (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - York - Aproved, 1964. (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - York - Court Case, 1962. (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - York - Denied, 1962-1964. (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - York - Parent Letters, 1962. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Subseries VII. Workbooks, 1958-1966., .7 cu. ft. (2 boxes) (Box 54-55)
    This subseries contains the work books maintained by the office staff, which consist mainly of school names listed alphabetically by location, with cities listed first, followed by counties.
    Box 54 contains the work books of an unknown employee, with no dates given, box 55 is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the employee who maintained the work book. The pages within each note book are arranged alphabetically with cities listed before counties.
    - Unknown (1), undated. (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Unknown (2), undated. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Unknown (A-F), undated. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Unknown (G-Y), undated. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Boucher, Hazel (1), 1964-1965. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Boucher, Hazel (2), 1964-1965. (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Costin, Frances (1), undated. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Costin, Frances (2), undated. (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Subseries VIII. Miscellaneous, 1957-1966., 2.36 cu. ft. (9 boxes) (Box 56-65)
    This subseries consists of items related to routine clerical functions of the board's office staff.
    - Notebook - Applications Recieved, 1959-1962. (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Notebook, 1962 Oct - 1964 Mar. (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Notebook, 1964 Mar - 1964 Nov. (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Notebook, 1964 Nov - 1966 May. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, undated/1962. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Note Cards - City Student Assignment, 1960-1961. (Box 57)
      This box contains note cards which list a location, childs name, date of transfer, and which school the child was transfered to, along with the reason for the transfer. (Bulk)
      The cards in this box are arranged alphabetically by location, thereunder by students last name.
    - Note Cards - County Student Assignment, 1960-1962. (Box 58)
      The bulk of this box contains note cards which list a location, childs name, date of transfer, and which school the child was transfered to, along with the reason for the transfer.
    - Note Cards, 1960-1965. (Box 59)
      This box contains cards which are headed by a location name, followed by a list of dates.
      The cards in this box are arranged alphabetically by location.
    - Desk Calendar, 1957. (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Desk Calendar, 1958. (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Desk Calendar (A), 1959. (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Desk Calendar (B), 1959. (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Desk Calendar - Hilton, 1960. (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Desk Calendar, 1961. (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Desk Calendar - Hilton, 1962. (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Desk Calendar, 1963. (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Desk Calendar, 1964. (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Desk Calendar, 1965. (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Application Form, unknown. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Form Letters, unknown. (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Office Forms, unknown. (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Tally Sheet Forms, unknown. (Box 63, Folder 4)
- Series II. Personnel, 1957-1966., Extent: .35 cu. ft. (1 box). (Box 63)
  This series contains personnel documents such as salary reports and job applications for the members of the board, as well as, the office staff. There are also documents which describe each clerical position, in addition to memorandums related to office matters.